DANIEL STROOD

dstrood@gmail.com

Career Objective

As an IT support specialist with over 10 years of experience in corporate and professional environments supporting servers and users, I am looking to learn something new every day and contribute to a thriving IT team in a real, meaningful way.

Technical Skills

- Windows Server: Installation, configuration, storage, AD, Group Policy, Backups, Physical and Virtual
- Desktop: Installation, Troubleshooting, Office Suite, Browsers and Common Software, managed AV
- Software: Office 365, G Suite, VOIP, VMWare, Hyper-V, VirtualBox, Medical and Dental Industry Software
- Hardware: Design and build PCs and servers, wired and wireless network installation and troubleshooting
- Networking: Installation, DNS, DHCP, VPN, Ubiquiti, Cisco ASDM-IDM, VLANs, UBC Transmogrifier
- Operating Systems: Windows 98 through 10, Server 2003 through 2016, Mac OSX, Linux
- Languages: PowerShell, PHP, Java, JavaScript, HTML5/CSS, SQL Oracle, MySQL, Postgres

Soft Skills

- Clear and concise oral and written communication
- Exceptional patience and customer service
- Logic-based, methodical troubleshooting

Work Experience:

Dragon Veterinary, Halifax NS

Nov 2018 - Jan 2020

- As technical support director, provided all levels of technical support for new and existing customers using Dragon Medical dictation software
- Onboarding and training of all new users, most of whom were doctors and veterinarians
- Training and escalation support for junior members of technical support and sales teams
- Also took sales calls and participated in executive planning and decision making sessions
- Created a pipeline in PHP to translate sales from Squarespace to the CRM Keap.

Tekworks, Delta BC Mar 2015 – Mar 2018

- Provided all aspects of support for over 100 professional clients with small MSP
- Office 365 Partner: upsold, provisioned, deployed, managed and troubleshot Office 365
- Thrived when taking ownership of issues and stewarding projects through to completion
- Introduced ticketing system, and among other projects, created a local inventory system (in PHP) to help improve efficiency and reduce unnecessary equipment purchases

IBI Group, Vancouver BC

May 2009 - Mar 2015

- Provided technical support for 150 local and 550 remote users
- Configured and supported PCs and Macs, hardware, software, printers and plotters
- Managed daily, weekly, and monthly tape backups using Symantec Backup Exec
- Helped administer over a dozen servers, both physical and virtual using VMware
- Wrote several PowerShell scripts in wide use including one to detect any improperly placed folders on the project server

Mark Anthony Group, Vancouver BC (Co-op)

May 2008 - August 2008

- Provided technical support on-site and via phone and email to all departments
- Experience using and supporting MS Exchange, AD, Cisco VOIP phones and VPN
- Created, modified, and applied Norton Ghost images on many different system configurations

Harbour City Bingo, Nanaimo BC

August 2005 - July 2007

• Bingo caller, cashier and shift supervisor in a high-paced, high-stress environment

NCO Customer Service and Tech Support Agent, Nanaimo BC

July 2003 - August 2005

• Provided high-level technical support (Levels 2 and 3) with a very high customer satisfaction rating

Education:

BCIT: Computer Information Technology Diploma Program

2007 – 2009

Covered a wide range of topics for both a System Administrator position, including Windows and Linux system administration, networking, network security and project management, as well as programming courses including web design, OO Java and software design patterns, PHP, MySQL and Oracle DB administration.